When new students arrive at Bodwell
新入生がボドウェルに入学した際、
they are all given a placement test to determine
すべての生徒にプレスメントテストを実施します。
if their level of English is high enough to be successful
これは、生徒達がレギュラーコースを受講できるレベルの
in the Regular Academic Program
英語レベルがあるかを図るものです。
The Academic and English Preparation Program (AEP)
アカデミック・イングリッシュ・プリパレーション・プログラム（AEP）は、
is a program that supports students
レギュラーコース受講に満たない英語レベルの
as they develop their English.
生徒達の英語力を上達させるための準備プログラムです。
The goal is for students to become competent
このプログラムの目的は、生徒達の
at reading, writing, speaking, and listening.
読解力、ライティング力、会話力、リスニング力を伸ばす事です。
Bodwell High School offers three terms per year.
ボドウェル高校では、3学期制をとっています。
Because of this accelerated learning,
この3学期制を使うと、例えば、AEPレベルの
it is possible for students to complete 1 to 3 terms of AEP
１から3までのレベルを1年間で終了することも可能で、
and still be on track to graduate
その後、レギュラーコースに進級し、
at the same time as Canadian students.
カナダ人の同級生と同じ時期に卒業することが可能となります。
For students beginning at Bodwell with weaker English,
英語力が低くスタートした生徒は、
the AEP program may delay graduation by 1-3 terms,
卒業が１～3学期遅れる可能性がありますが、
but the courses taken in AEP
AEPプログラム中にとったコースは
will benefit all students in all areas of learning,
すべての生徒にとって、その後の学習に有益となり
providing a strong English foundation
しっかりとした英語力になり
so that they can succeed in high school
高校での成功につながっていきます。
and achieve marks high enough to choose their desired university.
また、希望する大学へ必要な高い成績を修めることが出来ます。
Some reasons why your child
生徒がAEPプログラムを受講する理由は
has been placed in the AEP Program is because he/she
記述的な語彙、正しい文法を使って
is not able to write complex sentences using descriptive words and correct grammar,
複雑な文章を書く、文章力にかけていたり
cannot write a well-structured paragraph or essay
よく構成されたパラグラフやエッセイを書くことが、難しかったり
and cannot understand spoken English well or speak fluently
聞き取りの力が足りなかったり、英語を流暢に話せない場合です。
Your child is in level 1 because he/she
レベル１の生徒は、完全な文章で書くことや、
cannot write or speak in complete sentences,
話すことができず、英語を
and understands very little spoken English
殆ど理解できない場合です。
Your child is in level 2 because he/she
レベル２の生徒は、文章を書く際に、
makes many mistakes when writing sentences ,
まだ、多くの間違いをしたり、
cannot understand short stories or other texts,
短編小説やその他のテキストを、理解することができず、
and does not communicate well orally in English.
英語でうまく会話をする事が、難しい場合です。
Your child is in level 3 because he/she
レベル３の生徒は、
does not write intelligent sentences,
知的な文章力にかけ、構造的なパラグラフを
cannot write well-structured paragraphs
書くことがまだできません。
cannot fully understand higher level stories and text
高いレベルの小説やテキストを理解するのが難しく、
and makes many mistakes when communicating orally in English
会話をする際に、まだ多くの間違いがあります。
Your child is in level 4 because he/she
レベル４の生徒は、
needs more practice writing intelligent paragraphs and essays,
知的なパラグラフとエッセイを書くため、
makes grammar errors,
文法の間違いを少なくする練習が必要で、
is unable to think critically,
論理・批判的な判断や思考をする事が、難しい。
and needs more practice expressing oneself using higher level vocabulary.
また、レベルの高い語彙を使って、表現することがまだ難しいレベル。
Your child is ready to join the Academic Program when he/she
あなたのご子息は、アカデミックプログラムに進級する際は、
understands higher level literature and is able to talk about it
高いレベルの文献を理解し、それについて話す事ができ、
has good reading habits
よい読書習慣もみにつけ、
can write sentences, paragraphs and essays using a variety of sentences and vocabulary
さまざまな文章や語彙を使って、パラグラフ、エッセイを書くことができ、
can communicate confidently using good English.
英語で自信を持ってコミュニケーションできるレベルになっています。